Manfred Joa

Full Stack Web Developer

joamanfred@gmail.com · Portfolio · LinkedIn · GitHub · (718) 362-0081 · New York, NY

Profile

A Full Stack Web Developer with 5 years experience in high-level retail business management, customer service, and operations. A natural leader driven by the belief in leading by example and instilling a goal-oriented work ethic and big-results mindset, achieved through development of teams and fostering of collaborative and open environments conducive to inspiring passion and creative problem-solving. Excellent attention to detail, and leadership, listening, communication, and collaboration skills make an asset not just to any company, but its clients as well.

Skills

Front-End Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Tailwind CSS, UI component libraries **Back-End Technologies**: Node.js, Next.js, Python, Express, Flask, Django, JWT (JSON Web Token) Authentication **API Design and Development**: designing and building RESTful APIs, Postman, DRF (Django REST Framework) **Database Management**: MongoDB, Mongoose, Postgres, Peewee

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Git Workflows

Software Development Projects

June 2023 - September 2023

You & Meme - GitHub Client Repository | GitHub Server Repository | Deployed App

- Led team of 5 other developers to deploy a DR (Django, React) stack social media application in 1 week by delegating roles, testing and debugging, writing technical documentation, and fostering an environment of collaboration
- Integrated an API while utilizing SQL to create a backend and custom user model with a one-to-one relationship with the Django User model, to render a responsive, UX friendly design with posts, comments, and likes

Wine About It - GitHub Client Repository | GitHub Server Repository | Deployed App

- Collaborated with a team of 3 other developers as Code Owner to deploy a MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack ecommerce application using a NoSQL database, while performing code review and resolving merge conflicts
- Implemented user registration, sign-in, favorites, and cart features by utilizing React, Redux, state management, Tailwind CSS, user interfaces/UI components, JWT Authentication, and local storage to enable storage of user data

Hangman - GitHub Repository | Deployed App

- Coded game logic utilizing HTML, CSS, Canvas, DOM manipulation, and Java Script to design a frontend game
- Debugged game without referencing code by using problem-solving skills, identifying sources of coding issues, and unit testing accordingly to ensure usability and correct rendering of win/lose scenarios and drawing of hangman

Professional Experience

General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow

June 2023 - September 2023

• Building technical competency in full stack web development through a three month immersive dedicated to teaching programming languages and how to approach problems in order to build the next generation of web apps

Michaels Stores, Assistant Store Manager | Framing Manager

Aug 2010 - June 2023

- Executed daily operations and company initiatives through management of department managers, delegation, project management, and development of cross-functional teams achieved through cross training
- Created weekly store schedule using 600+ budgeted hours to establish full coverage, while managing payroll daily
- Exceeded custom framing sales goals during COVID, +30% Q4 2020 and FY 2022 +6% vs. company -2% by analyzing performance metrics and forecasting metrics to develop a performance improvement strategy to improve sales
- Prioritized developing customer relationships through personable customer service to create brand loyalty and utilized top-down selling techniques in selling value, resulting in store AUR \$150 vs. company AUR \$120

Education

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive

New York, New York June 2023 - September 2023

Purchase, New York

SUNY Purchase College

Bachelor of Arts in Arts Management, Magna Cum Laude